<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Klinkenberg</title>
    <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Klinkenberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Sharon Klinkenberg</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Online Lecturing</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2021-01-10-online-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2021-01-10-online-lecture/</guid>
      <description>I have been teaching a large scale course amidst the pandemic. In this post, I want to share my experiences with live lecturing online.
As the course has been around for quite some time, we had the lecture recordings of previous years at our disposal. Though simply providing these recordings would have been an easy solution, it did not feel right to throw this over the fence and call it a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Online Lecture Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2020-08-16-lecture-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2020-08-16-lecture-setup/</guid>
      <description>Strap in there, because this is going to be a deep dive. In a previous blog post, I already described how you could use open broadcast software (OBS) to overly a logo or presentation on your webcam feed, and switch between scenes while presenting. Based on that experience, I recently gave a two-hour online workshop taking this to the next level. The video below shows live interaction with the students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to the Mac</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2020-07-24-back-to-the-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2020-07-24-back-to-the-mac/</guid>
      <description>Remember that time I switched to windows? Well, after less than half a year, I already caved. Though I really tried to make this relationship work, in the end, there was just no love. Within a month of purchasing the DELL XPS 13, I already had significant regret. Not for Mac craving but because a new XPS was announced. An even slicker smaller better one than the one I just got.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Overlay</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/presentation_overlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/presentation_overlay/</guid>
      <description>So, the webinar on distance assessment was received quite well. Apart from the 200 attendees and now almost a hundred views on YouTube, I also received many questions on how I created the presentation overlay as can be seen in the video below.
 All about the layers To create this effect, I stacked some video layers and applied some chroma-keying to make it all look smooth. For this, I used the opensource open broadcast software called OBS studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing is everything</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_3/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in my previous grassroots blog, creating the animation I wanted for my 3D tracking video wasn&amp;rsquo;t that hard. This time I decided to follow my own advice and write the script first. After recording the audio in one session and trimming all the mistakes, I finally had an outline for the timing of the animation.
By importing the audio track into after effects, I was able to place the animation in such a way that it aligned perfectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I switched to windows!</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/switched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/switched/</guid>
      <description>#OMG it really happened. I switched to windows. After some twenty years of personal Mac use, I decided to switch. Now I’m not a complete noob to windows. I had my fair share of windows 98 trouble shooting back in the day. You know, the days where buying a new computer really meant getting a beige box with a DOS floppy, and finding a windows cd and drivers and solving al the problems associated with owning a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not 3D tracking yet</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_2/</guid>
      <description>So, it’s taken some time before I could really start this grassroot project, but I finally got the ball rolling. Looking at my own plan in my previous post I immediately went another rout. As I will base my first video on my earlier screencast on ANOVA (in Dutch), I decided to download the auto generated transcript from my YouTube channel. This gave me a rough outline with timestamps and all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D tracked knowledge video</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_1/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year again. The grass is turning green and so, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a new grassroots project. This time I&amp;rsquo;m going to dive into the world of 3D tracking in Adobe After Effects to create next level knowledge videos.
I was inspired by the awesome Peter McKinnon and his short tutorial on how to merge 3D graphics and video footage. I thought, how cool would it be to explain some statistical concepts and have it play out right in front of me on the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VR is so last year</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/spotlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/spotlight/</guid>
      <description>So, we’re done with VR for lecture recordings. Why? We just can’t see the presentation, let alone the laser pointer. VR is out. Enter the next generation of presenter tools: The Logi(tech) Spotlight. The spotlight presenter promises to boost your confidence. But let’s ignore that nonsense.
 The Spotlight does deliver the main goal we had of merging the campus lectures and the online weblectures. The remote is able to project a digital spotlight on the screen which of course can be captured by the weblecture registration software that we have here on campus.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>