<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>online | Klinkenberg</title>
    <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/tag/online/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/tag/online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>online</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016 Sharon Klinkenberg</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>online</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/tag/online/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Online Lecturing</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2021-01-10-online-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2021-01-10-online-lecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been teaching a large scale course amidst the pandemic. In this post, I want to share my experiences with live lecturing online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the course has been around for quite some time, we had the lecture recordings of previous years at our disposal. Though simply providing these recordings would have been an easy solution, it did not feel right to throw this over the fence and call it a day. To me, It felt like a signal to students that they could just figure it all out on their own. So the plan arose to provide live lectures. Spending way too many hours in zoom from March to June gave us the confidence to pull this off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2020-08-16-lecture-setup/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;previous blog&lt;/a&gt;, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OBS&lt;/a&gt; as my central hub. Though the whole process has become much more straightforward with the new OBS virtual webcam feature. Just hit the start virtual webcam button, and you can use it in any video conferencing tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/media/desk.png&#34; alt=&#34;Desk&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As can be seen from the picture above, I teach from my kids&#39; bedroom, armed with a couple of NERF&amp;rsquo;s. I use apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imore.com/how-use-sidecar-your-mac-and-ipad&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sidecar&lt;/a&gt; to use my iPad as a second monitor, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smallrig.com/smallrig-multi-functional-crab-shaped-clamp-with-ballhead-magic-arm-2164.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;clamped&lt;/a&gt; to a shelf with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://joby.com/be-en/griptight-pro-tablet-jb01395-config/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JOBI tablet grip&lt;/a&gt;. Placed at eye level to the right of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.canon.nl/cameras/eos-m50/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;my camera&lt;/a&gt;, it matches the scene when I look at the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/media/screen_grab.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screen grab&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My camera has a cheap plastic teleprompter mounted. With my iPhone logged into zoom. This lets me see my presentation when I speak, see my students when they ask questions, and Look straight into the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For audio, I use the amazingly versatile &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rode.com/microphones/videomicntg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;RØDE VideoMic NTG&lt;/a&gt;. Furthermore, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elgato.com/en/gaming/stream-deck-mini&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stream Deck&lt;/a&gt; makes tactile scene switching a breeze. So, without looking away from the camera, I can easily change the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of scenes, I essentially have two. One is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.studiobinder.com/blog/types-of-camera-shot-angles-in-film/#shoulder-level-shot&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shoulder level shot&lt;/a&gt;, and the second is a side by side shot with about two-third desktop and one-third camera, as can be seen above. Additionally, I have a &amp;ldquo;starting in 5 minutes&amp;rdquo; and a &amp;ldquo;Right Back&amp;rdquo; scene. During the break, I actually step out and get a cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the center monitor, you can see my desktop layout. I have OBS running at the right side. On the bottom left, the main zoom session, showing the chat and participants window. With so many students in a session, I sometimes have to mute all. The top left shows the YouTube Livestream panel. Yes, I stream the entire session for students who cannot attend the zoom session. Students that are constrained by timezones can view the lecture afterwards. Though some only watch the YouTube lecture at double speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As my internet service provider had a few outages, the web lecture recordings from the previous year served us well as a backup. Being logged in through my iPhone also proved to be very useful. Because I was still connected to students, I could tell them what was going on. And in one case, even continued my lecture on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the most important question, did our students actually enjoy this type of online lecture. Well, see for yourself in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;415&#34; style=&#34;margin: 10px 0 20px 0;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/d-hs6LPXtJ8?start=6286&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find all my lectures in the following &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PL5Zp3a0DklNyQlBF9MYorFzNlXxL5iDb-&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;playlist&lt;/a&gt; on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCt9z-wt6x8TbgJWCCSges8w&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt;. Looking at the time indication, you can see that my classes are about two hours long. Though I recently came across some articles stating that this is way too long to retain concentration, I think we should not underestimate students. Apart from these lectures, our students also attend &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/9KxgKDZxKr8?t=847&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;two-hour tutorial sessions&lt;/a&gt; and had weekly assignments. With the help of our outstanding tutors, I think we managed to pull off a pretty amazing online course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Online Lecture Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2020-08-16-lecture-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2020-08-16-lecture-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Strap in there, because this is going to be a deep dive. In a previous blog post, I already described how you could use open broadcast software (OBS) to overly a logo or presentation on your webcam feed, and switch between scenes while presenting. Based on that experience, I recently gave a two-hour online workshop taking this to the next level. The video below shows live interaction with the students. In this post, I will elaborate on how to connect all the applications and the hardware I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;415&#34;   src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/epsqxVKkYpE?start=2224&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/2020-07-24-back-to-the-mac/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;recently switched back to the mac&lt;/a&gt;, this post focusses on the setup for the mac only. Though it also works on windows. Sometimes even easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/media/camera.png&#34; alt=&#34;Camera Setup&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;connecting-obs-to-zoom&#34;&gt;Connecting OBS to zoom&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using OBS as the central hub for all video input means we have to get that video feed into zoom. For windows, this is easy with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/obs-virtualcam.539/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OBS webcam plugin&lt;/a&gt;. Though on the MAC, we have to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/obs-ndi-newtek-ndi%e2%84%a2-integration-into-obs-studio.528/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Network Device Interface (NDI) plugin&lt;/a&gt; to send out a video and convert that to a virtual camera, using the NDI Virtual input application, which is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ndi.tv/tools/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NDITools package at NDI.tv&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While zoom initially supported virtual camera input, the current version 5.0.4 seems to break that support. Though by unsigning the zoom application, this problem can be resolved quickly. Just paste the following command in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;codesign --remove-signature /Applications/zoom.us.app&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we are finally ready to stream video from OBS to zoom, and at the same time, we can record or stream the OBS output in HD, which lands us at the next problem. The only audio recorded is your voice and not the questions or conversations with your students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For OBS to pick up the sound from zoom, the audio needs to be redirected. For this purpose, the best application on the mac is &lt;a href=&#34;https://rogueamoeba.com/loopback/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Loopback&lt;/a&gt;. However, this will set you back $120. I tried a bunch of free alternatives, but none seemed to work consistently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this allowed me to record all the necessary audio and I could tell my students their faces would not end up online, the recordings do feel a bit eery, with student voices coming out of nowhere. To fix this problem, I added a &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/forum/resources/spectralizer.861/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;spectralizer in OBS&lt;/a&gt; to visualize the audio from my students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/presentation_overlay/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;previous post on using OBS&lt;/a&gt;, I described using a second monitor to use as input for zoom. I recently realized this is not even needed. Because you can screen share in zoom using the same virtual camera input. Screen sharing in zoom forces the presenter mode on the students. So, you, as a teacher, are assured they are not just staring at each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I am an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/119450864790538/photos/pb.119450864790538.-2207520000../121665361235755/?type=3&amp;amp;theater&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;award-winning amateur photographer&lt;/a&gt; :-) I have some camera gear lying around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, instead of using my laptop webcam, I connect my canon M50 camera through USB, added a continuous power source, and attached my 24mm F2 canon EF lens for a nice wide-angle. For audio, I recently switched to the RodeVideoMic NTG. Attached to the cold shoe of my camera, with a magic arm, it makes for a pretty compact recording setup. Though, the icing on the cake is the 3D printed camera mounted teleprompter, which I use with my iPhone running an extra zoom session. This way, it is easier to look straight into the camera at your students asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/media/hub.png&#34; alt=&#34;USB-C Hub&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With only one USB-c hub connected to my mac, the USB from the M50 and Mic go straight into the MacBook pro. The USB-c hub also supports a network cable, which is a must to ensure an uninterrupted connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tying-it-all-together&#34;&gt;Tying it all together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to run an online lecture, I fire up zoom on the computer and iPhone using the same account. iPhone in the teleprompter with all notifications and audio video turned off. I set the &amp;ldquo;starting in 5 minutes scene&amp;rdquo;, turn on screen sharing from 2nd camera (advanced tab) and hit record in OBS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
