<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Obs on Klinkenberg</title>
    <link>https://shklinkenberg.github.io/tags/obs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Obs on Klinkenberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Sharon Klinkenberg</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shklinkenberg.github.io/tags/obs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Online Lecturing</title>
      <link>https://shklinkenberg.github.io/post/2021-01-10-online-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shklinkenberg.github.io/post/2021-01-10-online-lecture/</guid>
      <description>I have been teaching a large scale course amidst the pandemic. In this post, I want to share my experiences with live lecturing online.
As the course has been around for quite some time, we had the lecture recordings of previous years at our disposal. Though simply providing these recordings would have been an easy solution, it did not feel right to throw this over the fence and call it a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Online Lecture Setup</title>
      <link>https://shklinkenberg.github.io/post/2020-08-16-lecture-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shklinkenberg.github.io/post/2020-08-16-lecture-setup/</guid>
      <description>Strap in there, because this is going to be a deep dive. In a previous blog post, I already described how you could use open broadcast software (OBS) to overly a logo or presentation on your webcam feed, and switch between scenes while presenting. Based on that experience, I recently gave a two-hour online workshop taking this to the next level. The video below shows live interaction with the students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Overlay</title>
      <link>https://shklinkenberg.github.io/post/presentation_overlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shklinkenberg.github.io/post/presentation_overlay/</guid>
      <description>So, the webinar on distance assessment was received quite well. Apart from the 200 attendees and now almost a hundred views on YouTube, I also received many questions on how I created the presentation overlay as can be seen in the video below.
 All about the layers To create this effect, I stacked some video layers and applied some chroma-keying to make it all look smooth. For this, I used the opensource open broadcast software called OBS studio.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>