<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Klinkenberg on Klinkenberg</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Klinkenberg on Klinkenberg</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Sharon Klinkenberg</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to the Mac</title>
      <link>/post/2020-07-24-back-to-the-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-07-24-back-to-the-mac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember that time &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/switched/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I switched to windows&lt;/a&gt;? Well, after less than half a year, I already caved. Though I really tried to make this relationship work, in the end, there was just no love. Within a month of purchasing the DELL XPS 13, I already had significant regret. Not for Mac craving but because a new XPS was announced. An even slicker smaller better one than the one I just got. So, initially, it was not windows that made me restless. I even invested heavily in learning the superuser tricks. Installing linux subsystem for windows, getting to know a bunch of shortcuts, and diving deep into system thingies to customize the heck out of the XPS. Setting up incremental backups and system restore points, the whole shebang.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the while, having that beautiful 4K touch screen to stare at. But wait, that screen is sucking the battery dry in no time. I ended up with a DELL powerbank because the ones I owned could not output 90 Watts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then came the updates. The OCD in me wants to have an up to date system. So, I installed the first update, and the second, and they kept coming. Not just the windows updates, but also an insane amount of DELL command center updates. It just would not stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/back_to_mac_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;MacBook Pro&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when I started to play around with Linux. Trying out different distros, but I always ran into one or the other problem. I was searching for solutions to problems I didn&amp;rsquo;t have on the Mac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, out of nowhere, came the salvation. Apple updated its MacBook Pro lineup. Bringing the 13-inch model back on spec with no keyboard issues anymore. So here I am, back in my walled garden, writing this blog on a Mac again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow Digitaal Toetsen</title>
      <link>/talk/2020-06-19-workshop-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2020-06-19-workshop-using-r/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;415&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/quxrQqjHlfA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duurzaam en robuuste inrichting van het digitale toetsproces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waar digitaal toetsen een paar maanden geleden nog slechts een optie was, is het nu plots een noodzaak geworden. Voor die afdelingen die het digitaal toetsen nog niet omarmt hadden kan dit behoorlijk overweldigend zijn. Nu de plannen voor het komend studiejaar gemaakt worden lijkt het ons het moment om met elkaar na te denken hoe met name digitale tentaminering idealiter ingeregeld zou moeten worden. Met die stip op de horizon kunnen digitale toets processen op een duurzame en robuuste manier worden ingericht.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In deze sessie zullen we in gaan op mogelijke werkprocessen, rollen rechten en het afbakenen en spreiden van verantwoordelijkheden. Met name dit laatste aspect moet de risico’s van uitval van medewerkers, gezien de COVID omstandigheden, in het toets proces minimaliseren.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online workshop: Introduction to R, Rstudio, Rstudio Cloud and Rmarkdown</title>
      <link>/talk/2020-07-07-digital-assessment-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2020-07-07-digital-assessment-workflow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;415&#34;  src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/epsqxVKkYpE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this workshop, we will dive into using Rmarkdown for presentations and reproducible research. We will use Rstudio cloud for education. At the end of this workshop, you will have a basic understanding of these tools and be able to apply it in your own research and courses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation Overlay</title>
      <link>/post/presentation_overlay/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/presentation_overlay/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So, the webinar on distance assessment was received quite well. Apart from the 200 attendees and now almost a hundred views on YouTube, I also received many questions on how I created the presentation overlay as can be seen in the video below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;385px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wzMtb3vFJm4?start=168&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-about-the-layers&#34;&gt;All about the layers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create this effect, I stacked some video layers and applied some chroma-keying to make it all look smooth. For this, I used the opensource open broadcast software called &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;OBS studio&lt;/a&gt;. The three essential layers needed are, of course, the webcam middle layer, a white image background layer, and the presentation layer, which is a PowerPoint with a chroma-key (green) background (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/files/Chroma_Key_PowerPoint.pptx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download Template&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- http://cogentstudios.com/how-to-set-opacity-obs-studio/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In OBS you need to set the webcam layer&amp;rsquo;s opacity to 40% by applying a a &lt;strong&gt;color key&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/-aXtar17E3o?t=64&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;filter&lt;/a&gt;, and you will get a more transparent image. To add the Powerpoint overlay, &lt;a href=&#34;https://superuser.com/questions/865094/how-can-i-view-a-powerpoint-slideshow-in-windowed-mode-ie-not-full-screen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;set Powerpoint to windowed mode&lt;/a&gt; and window &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/1V9rxexjyXU?t=615&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;capture this window in OBS&lt;/a&gt;. Watch &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/1V9rxexjyXU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this last video&lt;/a&gt; entirely for all the sources options available in OBS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final step, you just need to select a &lt;a href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/forum/threads/preview-output-on-second-monitor.112853/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;second monitor as output in OBS&lt;/a&gt; and use this second monitor as input for your conferencing software like zoom, meets, or teams. Well, here you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, am I satisfied? Nah, the text overlaying the eyes is just too distracting to me. I already experimented with using a half-width PowerPoint presentation, so you only use half of the screen. I&amp;rsquo;ll come back to that in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing is everything</title>
      <link>/post/gr_2019_blog_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gr_2019_blog_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;previous grassroots blog&lt;/a&gt;, creating the animation I wanted for my 3D tracking video wasn&amp;rsquo;t that hard. This time I decided to follow my own advice and write the script first. After recording the audio in one session and trimming all the mistakes, I finally had an outline for the timing of the animation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By importing the audio track into after effects, I was able to place the animation in such a way that it aligned perfectly. So I now have a synced animation that you can view in the clip below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;margin:15px 0 15px 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SN2aH8iyiVw?start=29&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the next puzzle will be the video recording. By first recording only the audio, I essentially ruined the possibility of doing a talking-head video. So, I plan to shoot some videos of only my hands explaining the animation without showing my head. And maybe try to do a lip-sync recording for a few parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you missed the previous posts on my grassroots project, you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;find them here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I switched to windows!</title>
      <link>/post/switched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 14:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/switched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#OMG it really happened. I switched to windows. After some twenty years of personal Mac use, I decided to switch. Now I’m not a complete noob to windows. I had my fair share of windows 98 trouble shooting back in the day. You know, the days where buying a new computer really meant getting a beige box with a DOS floppy, and finding a windows cd and drivers and solving al the problems associated with owning a computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the Mac was a big relief. It just worked. And, in a time where I needed to get actual work done, and I could afford a Mac, it was a very welcome relief. I managed for years to alleviate the price tag by selling after about two years, and getting a very reasonable return. So I went from a 12” MacBook to a 15” and then the black 13”, after which I stayed with the second generation MacBook air for two consecutive units, and eventually landing back at 12” with the 2015 MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there it started to lag. As I started to get restless and wanting to update, there was no update available. So I waited, and waited, but a significant update fell short. As I wanted to stay with the small form factor, the 2019 discontinuation of the 12” model was a major disappointment. So, I stuck to my 12” until it started to show problems with charging, battery life and random quirks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new Machine was inevitable but witch one? As the departure from the 12” would land me in a category of Macs that was plagued by keyboard issues and were not on par with today’s processing specs, the decision to switch started to loom. There was a sparkle of hope with the introduction of the 16” MacBook pro, but the keyboard and spec update stayed limited to the largest Machine of the bunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/xps13.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;XPS 13&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here I am, typing this blog on a DELL XPS 13” only slightly larger than my 12” MacBook, but with an intel 10th gen CPU, 16 gigs of RAM and a 512 SSD. Throwing on a 4K touch screen with a 10% discount, costed a fraction of the price of a Mac. Though windows 10 is the real price to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As being formally trained in the adobe suite, and wanting the full-fledged system integration of outlook exchange for work, going with a Linux distro only was not an option. Though I do plan on going for a dual boot at one point, for now I’ll stick to windows 10. The first week has been pretty painless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not 3D tracking yet</title>
      <link>/post/gr_2019_blog_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gr_2019_blog_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, it’s taken some time before I could really start this grassroot project, but I finally got the ball rolling. Looking at my own plan in my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.klinkenberg.amsterdam/post/gr_2019_blog_1/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; I immediately went another rout. As I will base my first video on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Q86DiHcuOVE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;earlier screencast on ANOVA&lt;/a&gt; (in Dutch), I decided to download the auto generated transcript from my YouTube channel. This gave me a rough outline with timestamps and all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading through the transcript, it became clear this was much too long. So, I wrote a shortened script that is much more to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up, was creating the graph I want to show in the video. Writing some R code, quickly landed me the plot I wanted. In the next step I followed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/prnmH3YVrQo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;instruction that Peter Farago laid out in the video&lt;/a&gt; below (left), and fired up illustrator to import my PDF. There, adding layers was easy. But getting the right path into the correct layer was a bit of a puzzle. Turning paths on and off, showed me which vector element was what. Making it easier to identify where everyting needed to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;margin:15px 0 15px 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:350px;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/prnmH3YVrQo&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:350px;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-iXhbMjQoNU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a lot of mistakes along the way, but I will spare you that pain. In the final Illustrator step, a quick CMD-A selected everything. Turning all the line colors white, made sure I could see the plot in After Effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/prnmH3YVrQo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Peter’s instructions&lt;/a&gt; were still very helpful as I initially forgot to convert the vector layers to shapes. Now that this is all covered, I could create a trim path to animate the individual lines. I’m now creating the animation as we speak. You can watch the preview above (right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the problems with animating is the timing. How long should each part be visible. For that, it might be easier if I first record the script and tune the animation accordingly. I will follow up on this progress in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naar een inrichtingsmodel voor flexibele en veilige toetsafname</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-05-24-inrichtingsmodel-flexibele-veilige-toetsafname/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-05-24-inrichtingsmodel-flexibele-veilige-toetsafname/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;415&#34;  src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/F8iGR4tILE4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharon Klinkenberg, voorzitter van SIG DT, startte de bijeenkomst met een droomscenario, voortbouwend op de 2e expertbijeenkomst in november 2018. Hij schetst een verdergaand droomscenario voor een student die een authentieke toets gaat maken. Stel je voor: “Je logt op een device in als student met je instellings ID, waarna een virtuele machine opstart, met daarin alleen de applicaties en bestanden die jij nodig hebt bij jouw toets. De toets start automatisch op, je werkt met de applicatie(s), levert uiteindelijk de bestanden/resultaten in en bij het afsluiten wordt een backup gemaakt van je materialen.” Dit is nu al technisch mogelijk. Maar is het schaalbaar, is er voldoende bandbreedte? Is het flexibel in de architectuur in te passen? Is het goed en flexibel koppelbaar met andere systemen, om bestanden in te leveren? En zijn de kosten beheersbaar? De vragen en antwoorden die deze droom oproept, kwamen in deze bijeenkomst aan bod met vier demo’s en daaraan gekoppelde werksessies. Deze demo&amp;rsquo;s worden verderop in dit artikel nader toegelicht.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D tracked knowledge video</title>
      <link>/post/gr_2019_blog_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gr_2019_blog_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s that time of the year again. The grass is turning green and so, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a new grassroots project. This time I&amp;rsquo;m going to dive into the world of 3D tracking in Adobe After Effects to create next level knowledge videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was inspired by the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/petermckinnon24&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Peter McKinnon&lt;/a&gt; and his short tutorial on how to merge 3D graphics and video footage. I thought, how cool would it be to explain some statistical concepts and have it play out right in front of me on the table. Looking at what &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCswCpVHySdNMVwIekKThGyQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AE Tutorials&lt;/a&gt; created, I could totally see this happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;margin:15px 0 15px 0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:350px;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m5_QznjzAlk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;width:350px;&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4aaPSQcFpZg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the grassroots project got approved and we&amp;rsquo;re going to do this. The goal is of course to create a few clips, but also to see how viable it is within the confounds of my own desktop computer and the Adobe CC suite. To answer this question, I will document my findings in this blog series. And if all goes well, I&amp;rsquo;ll create a video on how to do this on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is looking fairly easy, but I reckon we&amp;rsquo;ll bump into problems along the way. What we need to do is: Create some vector graphics and formula&amp;rsquo;s to use in the video. In my case, I will be making them in R, exporting to PDF and layering them in illustrator. Next up is to create a storyboard. Shoot a video, and finally edit it all together in after effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the plan at least. I will be doing a remake of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Q86DiHcuOVE&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;earlier&lt;/a&gt; analysis of variance &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/lZqwTzCb_0A&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt;. And if all goes well, I&amp;rsquo;ll tackle the fundamentals of null hypotheses testing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De weg naar Digitaal Toegankelijk Toetsen</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-03-14-ntt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-03-14-ntt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this talk we discussed the state of large scale digital assessment in higher education and what is needed to facilitate accessibility. The main take away, first make sure you have an established infrastructure for regular digital assessment and build your &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Accessibility&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;accessibility&lt;/a&gt; layer on top of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My challenge to the National network on Accessibility Assessment: Write a model policy memorandum which outlines the needs and course of action to facilitate accessible digital assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cinop.nl/home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CINOP&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.handicap-studie.nl/home.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Handicap+Studie&lt;/a&gt; for inviting me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of Assessment for Remediation</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-02-19-assessment-remediation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-02-19-assessment-remediation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub on Rstudio</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-02-14-bds-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-02-14-bds-github/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical basis for experimentation</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-01-07-stat-basis-exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-01-07-stat-basis-exp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expertbijeenkomst Veilig en veelzijdig toetsen op mobiele apparaten</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-11-13-assessment-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-11-13-assessment-mobile/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geen flexibilisering zonder digitaal toetsen</title>
      <link>/talk/2019-11-06-owd2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2019-11-06-owd2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Topic also covered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scienceguide.nl/2018/11/onderwijs-moment-plek/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Scienceguide.nl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
